const quizData = [
{
    "question": "421. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 45;\nint b = 55;\nint result = --a - ++b + a++ - b--;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "44",
    "b": "45",
    "c": "46",
    "d": "47",
    "correct": "c"
},
{
    "question": "422. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `counter`?",
    "code": "int counter = 300;\ncounter = counter-- - --counter + ++counter - counter--;\n",
    "a": "300",
    "b": "299",
    "c": "298",
    "d": "297",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "423. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 125;\nnum = ++num - num-- + --num - num++;\n",
    "a": "125",
    "b": "124",
    "c": "123",
    "d": "122",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "424. What is the result of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 90;\nint b = 10;\nint result = ++a - b-- + a++ - --b;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "90",
    "b": "91",
    "c": "92",
    "d": "93",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "425. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 150;\nvalue = value-- - --value + ++value - value++;\n",
    "a": "150",
    "b": "149",
    "c": "148",
    "d": "147",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "426. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int x = 110;\nint y = 20;\nint z = x-- - --y + ++x - y++;\nSystem.out.println(z);\n",
    "a": "110",
    "b": "111",
    "c": "112",
    "d": "113",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "427. What will be the final value of `counter` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int counter = 80;\ncounter = counter++ - --counter + ++counter - counter--;\n",
    "a": "80",
    "b": "79",
    "c": "78",
    "d": "77",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "428. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 95;\nint b = 25;\nint result = --a - ++b + a++ - b--;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "95",
    "b": "96",
    "c": "97",
    "d": "98",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "429. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 200;\nvalue = ++value - value-- + --value - value++;\n",
    "a": "200",
    "b": "199",
    "c": "198",
    "d": "197",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "430. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 55;\nnum = --num - num++ + ++num - num--;\n",
    "a": "55",
    "b": "54",
    "c": "53",
    "d": "52",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "431. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 60;\nint b = 40;\nint result = a-- - ++b + --a - b++;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "60",
    "b": "59",
    "c": "58",
    "d": "57",
    "correct": "c"
},
{
    "question": "432. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `counter`?",
    "code": "int counter = 350;\ncounter = ++counter - counter-- + --counter - counter++;\n",
    "a": "350",
    "b": "349",
    "c": "348",
    "d": "347",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "433. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 275;\nnum = num++ - --num + ++num - num--;\n",
    "a": "275",
    "b": "274",
    "c": "273",
    "d": "272",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "434. What is the result of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 85;\nint b = 15;\nint result = ++a - b++ + a-- - --b;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "85",
    "b": "86",
    "c": "87",
    "d": "88",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "435. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 125;\nvalue = --value - value++ + ++value - value--;\n",
    "a": "125",
    "b": "124",
    "c": "123",
    "d": "122",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "436. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int x = 300;\nint y = 50;\nint z = x++ - --y + ++x - y++;\nSystem.out.println(z);\n",
    "a": "300",
    "b": "301",
    "c": "302",
    "d": "303",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "437. What will be the final value of `counter` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int counter = 80;\ncounter = counter-- - --counter + ++counter - counter++;\n",
    "a": "80",
    "b": "79",
    "c": "78",
    "d": "77",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "438. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 45;\nint b = 55;\nint result = --a - ++b + a++ - b--;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "45",
    "b": "46",
    "c": "47",
    "d": "48",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "439. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 300;\nvalue = ++value - value-- + --value - value++;\n",
    "a": "300",
    "b": "299",
    "c": "298",
    "d": "297",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "440. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 150;\nnum = num-- - --num + ++num - num++;\n",
    "a": "150",
    "b": "149",
    "c": "148",
    "d": "147",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "441. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 90;\nint b = 30;\nint result = a++ - --b + ++a - b--;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "90",
    "b": "91",
    "c": "92",
    "d": "93",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "442. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `counter`?",
    "code": "int counter = 200;\ncounter = --counter - counter++ + ++counter - counter--;\n",
    "a": "200",
    "b": "199",
    "c": "198",
    "d": "197",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "443. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 350;\nnum = num++ - --num + ++num - num--;\n",
    "a": "350",
    "b": "349",
    "c": "348",
    "d": "347",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "444. What is the result of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int x = 70;\nint y = 20;\nint z = --x + y++ - ++x - y--;\nSystem.out.println(z);\n",
    "a": "70",
    "b": "71",
    "c": "72",
    "d": "73",
    "correct": "c"
},
{
    "question": "445. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 400;\nvalue = ++value - value-- + --value - value++;\n",
    "a": "400",
    "b": "399",
    "c": "398",
    "d": "397",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "446. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 120;\nint b = 60;\nint result = a-- - ++b + --a - b++;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "120",
    "b": "121",
    "c": "122",
    "d": "123",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "447. What will be the final value of `counter` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int counter = 500;\ncounter = counter++ - --counter + ++counter - counter--;\n",
    "a": "500",
    "b": "499",
    "c": "498",
    "d": "497",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "448. What is the output of the following Java code?",
    "code": "int a = 150;\nint b = 50;\nint result = ++a - b-- + a++ - --b;\nSystem.out.println(result);\n",
    "a": "150",
    "b": "151",
    "c": "152",
    "d": "153",
    "correct": "b"
},
{
    "question": "449. After executing the following code, what will be the value of `value`?",
    "code": "int value = 225;\nvalue = value++ - --value + ++value - value--;\n",
    "a": "225",
    "b": "224",
    "c": "223",
    "d": "222",
    "correct": "a"
},
{
    "question": "450. What will be the final value of `num` after executing this code?",
    "code": "int num = 100;\nnum = num-- - --num + ++num - num++;\n",
    "a": "100",
    "b": "99",
    "c": "98",
    "d": "97",
    "correct": "a"
},
];
    
    


const quiz = document.getElementById('quiz');
const answerEls = document.querySelectorAll('.answer');
const questionEl = document.getElementById('question');
const codeEl = document.getElementById('code');
const a_text = document.getElementById('a_text');
const b_text = document.getElementById('b_text');
const c_text = document.getElementById('c_text');
const d_text = document.getElementById('d_text');
const submitBtn = document.getElementById('submit');

let currentQuiz = 0;
let score = 0;
let selectedAnswers = [];

loadQuiz();

function loadQuiz() {
    deselectAnswers();

    const currentQuizData = quizData[currentQuiz];

    questionEl.innerText = currentQuizData.question;
    codeEl.innerHTML = `<pre><code class="language-java">${currentQuizData.code}</code></pre>`;
    a_text.innerHTML = currentQuizData.a;
    b_text.innerHTML = currentQuizData.b;
    c_text.innerHTML = currentQuizData.c;
    d_text.innerHTML = currentQuizData.d;

    hljs.highlightAll(); // Apply syntax highlighting
}

function deselectAnswers() {
    answerEls.forEach(answerEl => answerEl.checked = false);
}

function getSelected() {
    let answer;

    answerEls.forEach(answerEl => {
        if (answerEl.checked) {
            answer = answerEl.id;
        }
    });

    return answer;
}

submitBtn.addEventListener('click', () => {
    const answer = getSelected();

    if (answer) {
        const currentQuizData = quizData[currentQuiz];
        const correctAnswerText = document.getElementById(currentQuizData.correct + "_text").innerText;
        const selectedAnswerText = document.getElementById(answer + "_text").innerText;

        if (answer === currentQuizData.correct) {
            score++;
            alert(`Correct! You selected "${selectedAnswerText}".`);
        } else {
            alert(`Incorrect! You selected "${selectedAnswerText}". The correct answer is "${correctAnswerText}".`);
        }

        selectedAnswers.push({
            question: currentQuizData.question,
            code: currentQuizData.code,
            selected: selectedAnswerText,
            correct: correctAnswerText,
            isCorrect: answer === currentQuizData.correct
        });

        currentQuiz++;

        if (currentQuiz < quizData.length) {
            loadQuiz();
        } else {
            showResults();
        }
    } else {
        alert("Please select an answer!");
    }
});

function showResults() {
    quiz.innerHTML = `
        <h2 style="text-align: center; font-size: 2rem;">Quiz Results</h2>
        <p style="font-size: 1.5rem; text-align: center;">You answered ${score}/${quizData.length} questions correctly</p>
        <div style="margin-top: 2rem; max-height: 400px; overflow-y: auto; padding: 1rem; border: 1px solid #ccc; border-radius: 10px;">
            <h3 style="text-align: center; margin-bottom: 2rem;">Detailed Summary</h3>
            <ul style="list-style-type: none; padding: 0; font-size: 1.2rem;">
                ${selectedAnswers.map((result, index) => `
                    <li style="margin-bottom: 1.5rem;">
                        <strong>Question ${index + 1}:</strong> ${result.question}<br>
                        <pre><code class="language-java">${result.code}</code></pre>
                        <strong>Your Answer:</strong> ${result.selected} (${result.isCorrect ? '<span style="color: green;">Correct</span>' : '<span style="color: red;">Incorrect</span>'})<br>
                        ${!result.isCorrect ? `<strong>Correct Answer:</strong> ${result.correct}` : ''}
                    </li>
                `).join('')}
            </ul>
        </div>
        <div style="text-align: center; margin-top: 2rem;">
            <button onclick="location.reload()" style="font-size: 1.2rem; padding: 0.8rem 1.5rem; background-color: #8e44ad; color: #fff; border: none; cursor: pointer;">Reload Quiz</button>
        </div>
    `;

    hljs.highlightAll(); // Apply syntax highlighting in the summary
}
